Hey English learners, welcome to this A1
English listening practice video. Today
I'm gonna talk about some different
customs
in the US and in Mexico.
I've lived in both of these countries
and I have a lot of experience with the
different customs in these different
cultures.
So hopefully you find this topic
interesting. Uh many people like hearing
about my experience living in Mexico
uh because it's interesting to live
abroad and experience
these differences in culture and in
customs. So that's what I'm going to
talk about today. And remember that if
you want my help to understand fast
English, make sure to sign up to become
a listening time member so you can watch
my listening practice seminars in which
I help you understand English when
people speak fast. So that link is down
below. Okay, let's talk about some
different customs in the US and in
Mexico. The first thing I want to talk
about is meals. Uh, eating breakfast,
lunch, and dinner. These are meals.
Let's talk about the different uh meal
times in the US and in Mexico. Uh in the
US
uh lunch is usually between 12 and 100
p.m. usually and it's usually not the
biggest meal of the day. So sometimes
people eat a lot, but often it's not a
heavy meal, it's a light meal. Uh so
perhaps someone might just eat a
sandwich for example. Uh but people can
also eat a hot meal maybe. Uh, it
depends on the person, but lunch usually
isn't the biggest meal of the day. And
sometimes people eat lunch at their
office while they're working or in their
car uh on their lunch break uh when they
have a break from work. Uh, so this is
different in Mexico. In Mexico, lunch is
later in the day. It's usually between 2
and 4 p.m. So maybe around 300 p.m. on
average. Uh, and it's usually the
biggest meal of the day. This is usually
when people eat the most. People might
go to restaurants
uh around this time. So, you see a lot
of people at restaurants at 300 p.m.
3:30 p.m. This is very typical. It's
common. uh in the US uh you don't see as
many people at restaurants at that time
because that's too late for lunch in the
US and it's too early for dinner, right?
Um, in the US, dinner is typically
around 6, 6:30, 7 p.m. Dinner is usually
served around that time. Uh, and dinner
is usually the biggest meal of the day.
This is when people eat the most.
And when I was a kid, I always ate
dinner with my family, my parents and my
sister, and we ate almost every day uh
at the same time. Um, we ate dinner
around 6:30 p.m. and we
sat down together and my mom uh cooked a
big meal for us. This was the most
important meal of the day for me and my
family when I was growing up. And this
is when restaurants are the busiest. You
see many people at restaurants around
dinner time in the US. In Mexico, dinner
is later. Uh it's usually between
and 10 p.m. maybe. And usually it's not
too heavy. It's not a really big meal
because lunch is typically the biggest
meal. And for example, my wife's family
often eats sweet foods
for dinner. Um, not everyone does that,
but uh they uh often eat snacks and
sweet foods uh for dinner. But uh there
are many different things people might
eat for dinner in Mexico. Uh, and it's a
little strange for many of us to think
about eating dinner that late. It's hard
to imagine eating dinner at 900 p.m.,
for example. That's not typical in the
US. All right, let me talk about another
custom. uh the custom of arriving on
time or arriving late. In the US, most
people think that it's normal to arrive
on time for events, parties,
appointments,
etc. They don't want to be late. It's
not good to be late. In the US, of
course, sometimes people arrive late.
It's not always a problem, but in
general, people think that it's good to
arrive on time to things. In Mexico,
this is less strict.
Many people arrive late to different
events or appointments,
meetings,
uh, parties.
And often the other people don't get
mad. And I remember uh arriving at a
birthday party in Mexico that started at
6:00 p.m. or they told us that it
started at 6:00 p.m. and we arrived at
6:00 p.m. and nobody was there. and the
host, the person who was having the
party, they weren't even ready for us to
come inside yet. And this shows the
difference in culture. In the US, if
someone says that uh a birthday party is
going to start at 6:00 p.m., it's going
to start at 6:00 p.m.
If you show up at 6:00 p.m., you arrive
at 6. That's normal. But in Mexico, it's
normal for people to arrive late. and
sometimes very late to parties. I
remember that uh at that party uh people
came at like 700 p.m. or later even uh
but the party was uh supposed to start
at 6 p.m. So, uh, some people like, uh,
when, uh, a culture, um, is less strict
about arriving on time. Uh, some people
like punctuality,
meaning they like when people are on
time. People have different opinions
about this and you probably prefer one
or the other. Um, I like being on time,
but that's just me. All right. One other
custom I want to talk about is
greetings. When you say hello and
goodbye to people in Mexico, it's common
to give people a kiss on the cheek. Uh,
usually you don't touch your lips to
their skin. Uh, but you make the sound,
you touch your cheeks together. And
women do this with other women. Men do
it with women as well. Um, and people do
this even if you don't know the person
very well. Even if you don't know them
that well, you probably still greet them
with a kiss on the cheek. It depends.
Sometimes you don't do this, but I did
this many times when I lived in Mexico.
This was new for me. It was something
that I had to adapt to when I lived in
Mexico because in the US, this is not a
common greeting. Some people do this,
but usually it's people who they're very
close with and typically older people
might do this. It's not common to see
young people give a kiss on the cheek. I
don't remember seeing that uh in the US.
So this is not a common greeting in the
US and so it can be a little strange
when someone from the US goes to Mexico
and uh people greet them like this. Uh
you have to uh realize that this is a
very different custom in the two
countries. In the US, it's common to
give people a handshake in some
situations
or uh it's also common to give a hug.
Different types of hugs uh depending on
the situation.
It depends on how well you know the
other person. If you know them really
well and you're really close to them,
um, you might have a different type of
greeting than
someone who you don't know well at all.
There are different types, different
ways to greet people in the US, but
normally people don't give each other a
kiss, especially if they don't know each
other well. But it depends. Like I said,
there are many other examples of customs
that are different in the US and in
Mexico, but those are a few that I
wanted to talk about. Hopefully, this
video was helpful for you. I know it was
probably challenging for some of you. I
don't only use A1 language in my A1
videos because the purpose of an A1
listening practice video is to challenge
you and help you get to the next level
to A2. So there are some things I say
that are challenging, but that's okay.
If you are at an A1 level, you should
listen to things that are above that
level. Okay, thank you for watching and
remember that you can check out my
listening practice seminars that will
help you understand fast English. If you
want those, you can go down below and
click on the link to sign up. All right,
thank you so much for watching this
video and I'll talk to you in the next